Guide to the Radical and Labor Pamphlets Collection, 1896-1967, bulk 1911-1954 RL.11741
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Radical and Labor Pamphlets collection
1896-1967, bulk 1911-1954
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.11741
14.5 Linear Feet 720 items
The Radical and Labor Pamphlets Collection (1896-1967) includes approximately 720 pamphlets and other ephemeral publications relating to communism, socialism and other left-wing movements as well as to labor organizations and trade unions. There are some additional pamphlets related to anti-communist movements and some examples of Soviet propaganda.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Some of the pamphlets are rapidly deteriorating due to the acidic composition of their paper. To protect the most severe cases from further deterioration yet still make them available to researchers, many of them were photocopied on acid-free paper. These use copies are filed in the main collection and the originals are closed to use.
Provenance
The Radical and Labor Pamphlets Collection was transferred from Duke University's William R. Perkins Library to the Rubenstein Library in 1961.
Arrangement
The pamphlets are arranged by subject categories, with the largest groups relating to the activities and membership of the Communist and Socialist parties.
Collection Overview
The Radical and Labor Pamphlets Collection spans the years from 1896 to 1967, with the bulk of the dates falling between 1911 and 1954, and is made up of publications relating to communism, socialism and other left-wing movements as well as to labor parties and trade unions. Subjects represented are: the Communist Party in the U.S. and Great Britain; socialism in the U.S. and other countries; radical youth organizations; political trials and persecutions of radical activists; labor organizations; anti-fascist and pacifist movements; anarchist organizations; anti-Communist propaganda; Soviet propaganda; and Soviet-Western relations. Other significant topics include economic justice, electoral campaigns, human rights issues, the role of women and youth in activist movements, unemployment, housing, fascism in Spain and other contemporary war issues.
There are many important individual authors represented in this collection, including Israel Amter, Arthur Clegg, Georgi Dimitrov, Emma Goldman, Gilbert Green, Grace Hutchins, Mikhail Ivanovich Kalinin, Corliss Lamont, Clare Booth Luce, Philip Murray, Harry Pollitt, Karl Radek, Iosif Stalin, Lev Trotskii, and many others. Many pamphlets were produced anonymously under the aegis of institutions: these include the Communist Party, USA, Socialist Labor Party, Young Communist League, International Labor Defense, Civil Rights Congress, Communist International, Congress of Industrial Organizations, Farmer's Labor Unions, American Federation of Labor, Friends of the Soviet Union, and many more.
The pamphlets are arranged by subject categories, with the largest groups relating to the activities and membership of the Communist and Socialist parties. There is a small group of pamphlets chiefly made up of radical and labor song collections from 1912 to 1950. The majority of the pamphlets were produced in the United States and Great Britain, but there are also smaller groups of materials from Russia, India, Australia, Canada, China, Ireland, Italy, Brazil, the Philippines, and Mexico.
Many of these publications are ephemeral, that is, focused on urgent contemporary issues and generally intended for immediate consumption or short-term use. For this and for other reasons, they were often printed on poor quality paper which now shows signs of severe deterioration. The results are that few of these publications remain in circulation, and researchers may find many of them difficult to locate in library collections.
Socialist parties -- United States; Communism -- Soviet Union; Anarchism; Socialism; Propaganda, Anti-communist; Unemployment -- United States; Labor unions and communism; World War, 1939-1945 -- United States; United States -- Politics and government -- 1901-1953; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939; Socialist parties -- Europe; Pacifism; Working class -- Songs and music; Political persecution; Anti-fascist movements; International labor activities; Socialist Party (U.S.); Industrial Workers of the World; Communist Party of the United States of America; Communist Party of Great Britain; Young Communist League of the U.S.
- Communism, USA, 1907-1959; 229 pamphlets
  - Communist Party of America, 1907-1959; 66 pamphlets
    - Pamphlets from New York State, 1925-1955 and undated
      Arrangement
      Arranged chronologically, and within date groups, alphabetically by title.
      Scope and Contents
      Anonymous pamphlets published by the Communist Party of America in New York State. Many are related to political campaigns, but other topics include women's issues, unemployment, housing, youth programs, and World War II. Three pamphlets are not published by the Party but by Workers Library Publishers, the Party's publishing house.
      - For a Communist Party of Action, 1925 (Box 1)
      - Lenin Memorial Meeting..., 1925 (Box 1)
      - Another War Coming and the Workers Pay Its Price, 1930 (Box 1)
      - Struggles Ahead! Thesis on the Economic and Political Situation and the Tasks of the Communist Party..., 1930 (Box 1)
      - World-Wide Unemployment. 20,000,000 Unemployed, [1930?] (Box 1)
      - Communist Call to the Toiling Farmers, 1931 (Box 1)
      - 50,000,000 Unemployed; 150,000,000 Starving: World Capitalism's Crisis..., 1931 (Box 1)
      - Unemployment Relief and Social Insurance: The Communist Party Against the Capitalist Program of Starvation, 1931 [use copy] (Box 1)
      - Communist Election Platform. Against Imperialist War -- For Jobs and Bread Vote Communist!, 1932 [use copy] (Box 1)
      - The Democratic Twin of the Hoover Hunger Government, 1932 [use copy] (Box 1)
      - The Farmers' Way Out, 1932 [use copy] (Box 1)
      - Hoover, the Great Engineer After Four Years, 1932 New York State Communist Platform, 1932 (Box 1)
      - Working Women and the Elections, 1932 [use copy] Socialist Party: Words and Deeds, [1933?] (Box 1)
      - An Urgent Letter to Every Communist in New York, 1933 (Box 1)
      - Election Platform of the Communist Party, 1934 (Box 1)
      - Teachers! Where Do You Stand Today, 1934? 1934 (Box 1)
      - Piattaforma elettorale del Partito Comunista, 1936 [use copy] (Box 1)
      - Youth Faces the Elections, 1936 [use copy] (Box 1)
      - A Manual for Unit Educational Directors, 1937 (Box 1)
      - The Communist Election Platform, 1938 [use copy] (Box 1)
      - The La Follette Third Party. Will it Unite or Split the Progressive Forces? 1938 [use copy] (Box 1)
      - A Program for the 18th Assembly District, Kings County, 1938 (Box 1)
      - Prosperity and Progress for NY State Farmers, [1938?] (Box 1)
      - Death Penalty Demanded The Case of Georgia Against the Communist Party, [193-?] (Box 1)
      - Why Every Worker Should Join the Communist Party, [193-?] (Box 1)
      - Why You Should Vote Communist..., [193-?] [use copy] (Box 1)
      - The Constitution of the Communist Party of the USA, [1940?] (Box 1)
      - The Red Army, 1941 (Box 1)
      - Attack Hitler Now! A May Day Call, [1942?] [use copy] (Box 1)
      - The Man Who Didn't Forget, [1942?] (Box 1)
      - How to Get Jobs for All..., [1946?] [use copy] (Box 1)
      - What Do Communists Really Want? 1947 (Box 1)
      - 1948 Election Platform of the Communist Party, 1948 (Box 1)
      - State Legislative Program, 1949 (Box 1)
      - Patriotism Against McCarthyism, [1953?] (Box 1)
      - The Farm Crisis: A Program for Farm-Labor Unity..., 1955 (Box 1)
      - American Working Women and the Class Struggle, undated (Box 1)
      - Decent Homes to Live In: The Communist Position on Housing, undated (Box 1)
      - For a Labor Party in Westchester County..., undated (Box 1)
      - Give a Party for the Party, undated (Box 1)
      - Guide for Party Functionaries: Keep and Refer to When Confronted with Membership Problems, undated (Box 1)
      - How to Build It! undated [use copy] (Box 1)
      - Party Building: A Handbook for Branch Officers, undated (Box 1)
      - A People's Constitution for New York, n. d. (Box 1)
      - A Program for You: Platform of the Communist Party..., undated [use copy] (Box 1)
      - Questions and Notes on "The A.B.C. of Communism" ..., undated (Box 1)
      - Unite! For Peace, Democracy, Security, undated [use copy] (Box 1)
      - Who Ruptured Our Duck? What's the Deal for Veterans? undated (Box 1)
    - Other States, 1925-1950
      - Illinois: Vote for Workers' Candidates Endorsed by the Communist Party..., 1933 [use copy] (Box 2)
      - Illinois: Unite Against Hunger..., 1935 (Box 2)
      - Illinois: Platform of the Communist Party, State of Illinois, for the Election, November, 1936, 1936 (Box 2)
      - Illinois: Questions Guide for Club Discussion of the Reports of the Plenary Meeting..., 1950 (Box 2)
      - Illinois: Vote Communist! Smash the Bosses [sic] Program of Hunger and War! [193-?] (Box 2)
      - Massachusetts: A Confession of Faith..., 1937 (Box 2)
      - Massachusetts: Declaration of Principles and Constitution. .., 1937 (Box 2)
      - New Jersey: Hague over Jersey, [1938?] (Box 2)
      - Ohio: Into Mass Work..., [1934?] (Box 2)
      - Ohio: A Year in Review and Our Next Tasks..., 1935 (Box 2)
      - Ohio: Key Tasks: Tactics in the Trade Union Front ..., undated (Box 2)
      - Pennsylvania: ...From the Cradle of Liberty...to the Tomb of Fascism, 1937 (Box 2)
      - Texas: What the People of Texas Need: The Communist Program for the Lone Star State, 1946 (Box 2)
      - Virginia: Who Shall Rule Virginia, the People or the Byrd Machine? 1937 (Box 2)
    - Signed Pamphlets, 1907-1959; 75 pamphlets
      Issued by the Communist Party of America or by Communist Party-affiliated publishing houses such as New Century Publishers or Workers Library Publishers. Arranged alphabetically by author. Other pamphlets by Gil Green also can be found under "Young Communist League...," of which he was president, under the series "Communism, USA, Related Organizations."
      - Albertson, William. The Trucks Act: Michigan's Blueprint for a Fascist State, 1952 (Box 2)
      - Amter, Israel. Industrial Slavery -- Roosevelt's "New Deal," 1933 (Box 2)
      - Amter, Israel. Social Security in a Soviet America, 1935 (Box 2)
      - Amter, Israel. May Day 1941, 1941 [use copy] (Box 2)
      - Amter, Israel. Is the Socialist Party a Party of the Workers? undated [use copy] (Box 2)
      - Amter, Israel. A Program for Manhattan's Millions, undated [use copy] (Box 2)
      - Amter, Israel. The Truth about the Communists, undated [use copy] (Box 2)
      - Blake, George. Who Pays for the Cold War? 1949 (Box 2)
      - Browder, Earl R. Study Guide and Outline for the People's Front, undated (Box 2)
      - Burton, Bernard. A New Depression? 1949 (Box 2)
      - Burton, Bernard. The Big Lie of War "Prosperity, 11 1952 (Box 2)
      - Carlson, Frank. Let's Get Off the Dime, undated (Box 2)
      - Coleman, Jerry. A Square Deal for the Farmer, 1938 (Box 2)
      - Collins, Mary. Democracy in Danger, 1938 [use copy] (Box 2)
      - Collins, Mary. The Fight for Recovery, 1938 [use copy] (Box 2)
      - Cooper, Leo. Universal Military Training Program for Peace or Weapon for War? 1948 (Box 3)
      - Cowl, Margaret. The Soviet Union: Your Questions Answered, 1933 [use copy] (Box 3)
      - Cowl, Margaret. The High Cost of Living: How to Bring it Down, 1935 [use copy] (Box 3)
      - Cowl, Margaret. Women and Equality, undated (Box 3)
      - Eugene, Dennis. The Communists Take a New Look, 1956 (Box 3)
      - Foster, William Zebulon. Fight against Hunger..., 1930 (Box 3)
      - Foster, William Zebulon. Danger Signals for Organized Labor, 1953 (Box 3)
      - Foster, William Zebulon. Bibliography of Books and Pamphlets, undated (Box 3)
      - Foster, William Zebulon. 2nd Front Now, undated [use copy] (Box 3)
      - Friedman, Robert. How to Protect Yourself from the Atom Bomb, 1951 (Box 3)
      - Friedrich, G. Miss U.S.S.R. The Story of a Girl Stakhanovite, undated (Box 3)
      - Gannett, Betty. The Communist Party and You, 1946 (Box 3)
      - Gates, John. On Guard Against Browderism, Titoism, Trotskyism, 1951 (Box 3)
      - Gordon, Evelyn. Weaving the Future, 1937 (Box 3)
      - Green, Gil. The Truth about Soviet Russia, 1938 (Box 3)
      - Green, Gil. America Must Act Now! 1941 [use copy] (Box 3)
      - Green, Gil. New York's Wartime Election, 1942 (Box 3)
      - Green, Gil. Marxism and the World Today, 1944 (see also Communism, USA - Related Organizations for other works by Green) (Box 3)
      - Groetz, R. Ernst Thaelmann, the Leader of the German Workers, 1934 (Box 3)
      - Hall, Gus. Hands off Korea and Formosa, 1950 (Box 3)
      - Hall, Rob F. This 4th of July, 1776-1939, 1939 (Box 3)
      - Heckert, Fritz. What is Happening in Germany? 1933 (Box 3)
      - Hicks, Granville. Catholics, Communists and Democracy..., [194-?] (Box 3)
      - Hirsch, Carl. Terror at Trumball, 1955 (Box 3)
      - Howard, Milton. This 4th of July, 1938 (Box 3)
      - Hudson, Roy. Who Are the Reds? 1937 (Box 3)
      - Hudson, Roy. Two Questions on Winning the War, 1942 (Box 3)
      - Hutchins, Grace. Women and War..., 1932 (Box 3)
      - Hutchins, Grace. What Every Working Woman Wants..., 1935 (Box 3)
      - Kaye, Martin and Louise Perry. Who Fights for a Free Cuba? undated (Box 3)
      - Magil, Abraham B. The People's Message to Congress, 1938 (Box 3)
      - Magil, Abraham B. America Needs Earl Browder..., 1941 [use copy] (Box 3)
      - Millard, Betty. Women on Guard: How the Women of the World Fight for Peace, 1952 (Box 3)
      - Morris, George. The Black Legion Rides, 1936 (Box 4)
      - Morris, George. How Wall Street Picks Your Pocket, 1946 [use copy] (Box 4)
      - Morris, George. A Tale of Two Waterfronts, 1953 (Box 4)
      - Morris, Richard. What's Happening in Korea? undated (Box 4)
      - Murray, Sean. Ireland's Fight for Freedom and the Irish in the USA, 1934 (Box 4)
      - North, Joseph. Labor Faces '44's Challenge, 1944 [use copy] (Box 4)
      - North, Joseph. Verdict Against Freedom. Your Stake in the Communist Trial, 1949 (Box 4)
      - North, Joseph. Cuba's Revolution. I Saw the People's Victory..., 1959 (Box 4)
      - Parker, Alex. Organizing the Party for Victory over Reaction, 1953 (Box 4)
      - Platt, Leon. Building Socialism in the Soviet Union, [1929?] (Box 4)
      - Raymond, Harry. The Milk Steal, 1936 [use copy] (Box 4)
      - Reed, John. The Sisson Documents, [1907?] [use copy] (Box 4)
      - Richards, Dave. Milk for Millions..., undated (Box 4)
      - Richards, David H. Your Taxes: An Explanation and a Program, undated (Box 4)
      - Richards, Paul. Spotlight on Germany, 1948 (Box 4)
      - Ross, Allan Clunies. Reconversion: Security or Crisis? 1944 (Box 4)
      - Ruthenberg, Charles E. Why Every Worker Should Be a Communist and Join the Workers Party, undated [use copy] (Box 4)
      - Schirmer, Daniel B. The Truth about the MTA, undated (Box 4)
      - Shulman, Rubin. I Speak to My Neighbors, undated (Box 4)
      - Silverman, Harriet. J Louis Engdahl, Revolutionary Working Class Leader, 1935 (Box 4)
      - Spivak, John L. Pattern for American Fascism, 1947 (Box 4)
      - Starobin, Joseph. The True Story of Alter and Ehrlich, undated [use copy] (Box 4)
      - Sutton, Olive. Murder Inc. in Greece, 1948 (Box 4)
      - Tanaka, Giichi Baron. Japanese Imperialism Stripped: The Secret Memorandum of Tanaka ... [published by Workers Library, with the introduction reprinted from the Communist International], undated (Box 4)
      - Van Veen, Sadie. Our Children Cry for Bread, 1933 [use copy] (Box 4)
      - White, Eliot. The Rev. and Mrs. White Explain, undated (Box 4)
      - Williamson, John. Keynote Speech Delivered at the Communist Party State Ratification Conference in Youngstown, Ohio..., 1934 (Box 4)
      - Williamson, John. Davey Must Be Defeated! 1937 [use copy] (Box 4)
  - Related Organizations, 1931-1958; 26 pamphlets
    - Communist Political Association, after 1944 and undated
      - Constitution of the Communist Political Association, [after 1944] (Box 5)
      - Goldway, David. The Communist Political Association, [circa 1944] (Box 5)
      - Goldway, David. What New York State Needs, undated (Box 5)
    - The Young Communist League and Other Related Radical Youth Organizations, 1931-1958 and undated, bulk 1930s-1940s
      Arranged chronologically
      Organizations represented include the Young Communist League, the Young Pioneers of America, the International Student Union, and the Student League for Industrial Democracy. One pamphlet was issued under the auspices of the Anti-Fascist Youth Rally in Moscow, 1941. Five pamphlets were written by Gilbert Green, president of the Young Communist League.
      - Young Pioneers of America. Young Pioneers of America [Membership Book], 1931 (Box 5)
      - Green, Gil. Youth Confronts the Blue Eagle..., 1933 [use copy] (Box 5)
      - United We Stand for Peace and Socialism, 1935 (Box 5)
      - Young Communists and the Unity of the Youth, 1935 (Box 5)
      - Millet, Martha and Sam Strong. Scouting and the Boy Scout Jamboree, 1935 (Box 5)
      - Weis, Mac. In Flanders Field, 1935 (Box 5)
      - Green, Gil. Facing the 8th Convention of the Young Communist League, 1937 (Box 5)
      - Ross, Carl. Let's Pull Together for Jobs, Security, Democracy and Peace, 1938 (Box 5)
      - Starobin, Joseph. Life and Death of an American Hero..., 1938 (Box 5)
      - Little, John. Life for America's Sons and Daughters, 1939 (Box 5)
      - Anti-Fascist Youth Rally. Our Generation is in Danger, 1941 (Box 5)
      - Grant, Dave. Attack Now! Knock Out Hitler in '42, 1942 (Box 5)
      - Caller, Fay. In Freedom's Cause. Soviet Youth at War, 1943 (Box 5)
      - Starobin, Joseph. It's Up to You! [194-?] (Box 5)
      - Hall, Gus. Which Way for Young Americans? 1950 (Box 5)
      - Ward, Roosevelt. Toward Bright Tomorrows..., 1950 (Box 5)
      - Meana, Carlo. A Visit to Viet-Nam, 1956 (Box 5)
      - International Union of Students. Resolutions of the Vth I US. Congress, Peking..., 1958 (Box 5)
      - Green, Gil. Let's Fight Together! [circa 1936?] [use copy] (Box 5)
      - Hoemle, Edwin. Manual for Leaders of Children's Groups..., [circa 1923?] [use copy] (Box 5)
      - League for Industrial Democracy. Students in Revolt: The Story of the Intercollegiate League for Industrial Democracy..., [circa 1933?] (Box 5)
      - New York Youth Congress. No Slave Labor: Exposing Plans to Regiment Youth in Forced Labor Battalions: proposing a Real Program for Jobs and Training..., [circa 1940?] (Box 5)
      - Student League for Industrial Democracy (U.S.). Handbook of the Student League..., [circa 1934] (Box 5)
  - Political Trials, Persecutions and Deportations of American Communists and Other Radical Activists, 1916-1955 and undated; 28 pamphlets
    Issued by various groups and committees in defense of the civil rights of persecuted individuals or political groups in the United States.
    - Cockran, William B. "The Mooney Case": An Address by the Hon. W B. Cockran, 1916 (Box 6)
    - Dolson, James H. The Defense of a Revolutionary by Himself..., 1920 (Box 6)
    - People's Freedom Union. The Truth About the Lusk Committee..., 1920 (Box 6)
    - Evans, Elizabeth G. Outstanding Features of the Sacco-Vanzetti Case Together with Letters from the Defendants, 1924 (Box 6)
    - American Civil Liberties Union. "Unlawful Assembly" in Patterson, 1925 (Box 6)
    - Sugar, Maurice. A Negro on Trial for His Life..., 1935 (Box 6)
    - Colman, Louis. Lawrence Simpson's "Treason," 1936 (Box 6)
    - Dodd, Bella V. Swing Wide the Gates: Let Morris Schappes Be Free, 1941 (Box 6)
    - Schappes, Morris U. The Address to the Court..., 1941 (Box 6)
    - Yergan, Max. The Negro and Justice: A Plea for Earl Browder, 1941 (Box 6)
    - Ross, Carl. Let Freedom Ring for Earl Browder, 1942 (Box 6)
    - Green, Abner. United Nations in America, 1943 [use copy] (Box 6)
    - Civil Rights Defense Committee. Who Are the 18 Prisoners in the Minneapolis Labor Case? 1944 (Box 6)
    - Eisler, Gerhart. My Side of the Story, 1947 (Box 6)
    - Green, Abner. The Deportation Terror: A Weapon to Gag America, 1950 (Box 6)
    - The Deportation Drive vs. the Bill of Rights, 1951 (Box 6)
    - North, Joseph. Behind the Florida Bombings: Who Killed NAACP Leader Harry T. Moore and His Wife? 1952 (Box 6)
    - Green, Abner. The Walter-McCarran Law: Police-State Terror Against Foreign Born Americans, 1953 (Box 6)
    - Lightfoot, Claude. "Not Guilty!"...The Case against Claude Lightfoot, 1955 (Box 6)
    - Committee for Defense of the Pittsburgh Three. Musmanno Isn't Loading Coal -­ Just Baloney, undated (Box 6)
    - Committee for the Defense of Civil Rights of Communists. The Conspiracy Against Free Elections, undated (Box 6)
    - Committee in Defense of Carl Marzani. The Case of Carl Marzani, undated (Box 6)
    - Goldsmith, Len. Ideas Behind Bars? undated (Box 6)
    - Joint Committee to Defend WPA Workers. Terror Against the People: The Story of the WPA Witch Hunt, undated (Box 6)
    - The Moyer-Haywood Case and the US. Supreme Court, undated (Box 6)
    - National Office of the Socialist Party. "Not Guilty": Charge of Federal Judge Clarence W: Sessions in the Conspiracy Case Against Adolf Germer, et al., undated (Box 6)
    - Norman, John F. Murder in Jersey: The Story the Kefauver Committee Didn't Tell, undated (Box 6)
    - State, County and Municipal Workers of America. While You're Not Looking..., undated (Box 6)
- Anti-Fascist and Pacifist Radical Movements, 1933-1951 and undated, bulk 1930s-1940s; 25 pamphlets
  Arranged chronologically.
  Chiefly published in the U.S.. Communist and non-communist radical groups are represented. Most of the pamphlets are concerned with Nazi Germany, with fascism in Europe at large, and the threat of fascism in the U.S.
  - Committee of Expelled and Suspended City College Students. City College and War: Why Were Twenty-one Students Expelled? 1933 (Box 7)
  - The Fight for Communism in Germany, 1933 (Box 7)
  - National Committee to Aid Victims of German Fascism. Who Burned the Reichstag? 1933 [use copy] (Box 7)
  - Commission Investigating Fascist Activities. Women Under Hitler Fascism..., 1934 (Box 7)
  - Sonneburg Torture Camp, by an Escaped Prisoner, 1934 (Box 7)
  - Hitler Against the World. The World Against Hitler, 1935 (Box 7)
  - Strachey, John. Why Fascism Leads to War, 1935 (Box 7)
  - Franklin, John. National Defense, 1936 (Box 7)
  - Hart, Harold. The Cry for Peace, 1936 (Box 7)
  - The Menace of a New World War, 1936 (Box 7)
  - Rossi, Carlo. In the Dungeons of Mussolini..., 1936 (Box 7)
  - Blumenfield, Frank B. A Blueprint for Fascism..., 1937 (Box 7)
  - Hughan, Jessie W. What about Spain? 1937 (Box 7)
  - McMillen, Wayne. This Is Our Concern: A Statement to American Social Workers on Their Stake in the Civil War in Spain, 1937 (Box 7)
  - Pivert, Marceau. Action directe contre la guerre et le fascisme, 1938 (Box 7)
  - Pritt, Denis N. The Mosely Case, [1943?] (Box 7)
  - University Labor Federation [Great Britain]. Students in Action: The Story of a Life Against Fascism, [1943?] (Box 7)
  - Radvanyi, Netty. Anna Seghers [pseud.] [and] Constancia de la Mora Tell the Story of the Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee, [1944?] (Box 7)
  - Steel, Johannes. The Case for Peace, [194-?] (Box 7)
  - Montagu, Ivor G. S. Negotiation or War: Why We Need the Peace Pact, [1951?] (Box 7)
  - Freeman, Joseph. The Background of German Fascism, undated (Box 7)